

AGUS SYAHRIL

Address : Jln.Pitacandra No.33, Tatar

Pitaloka Kota Baru Parahiyangan,

Bandung.

Mobile 1 : +6281220310456 Mobile 2 : +6285703055572

E-mail : syahril agus@yahoo.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

ID. Card Number : 32.1708.060885.0024

Place/Date of Birth : Palembang / 6 Agustus 1985

Religion : Moslem

Language : English and Indonesia (Active and Passive)

Sex : Male Marital Status : Single

Hobby : Sport, Technology, R&D

Organization : HIMA Teknik Elektro, Al-HAQ

RESUME & SKILL

I have more than three years working Experience as Design Instrument Engineer in Energy Sector (Oil & Gas, Mining) familiar with ISA, AGA, NFPA standard, and one years experience as Signalling Data Engineer in Railway signaling. I like to explore my skill for a new knowledge especially in Electrical, Instrument & Control discipline.

Nowadays I am looking for a chance to expose for Construction, Installation, Precommissioning, Testing & commissioning, Automation.

ENGINEERING SOFTWARE SKILL:

- Instru Calc.
- Control Valve Sizing: First Vue, Performance Nxt.
- PSV Sizing : Size Master.
- Daniel Orifice Calculator.
- Dialux.
- MatLab, C++.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical Engineering sub majoring in Control and instrumentation, Maranatha Christian University, Bandung (2003-2009)

GPA : 3.03/4.00

Graduated From SMU XAVERIUS 1, Palembang (2000-2003)

Graduated From SLTP XAVERIUS MARIA, Palembang (1997-2000)

WORKING EXPERIENCES

1. PT.SARKU ENJINEERING UTAMA Electrical & Instrument Engineer (April 2016 – Current)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Endorse Engineering Design from Client's Engineering Consultant for construction.
- Fire Alarm Equipment selection for procurement process.
- Assist in FAT For LP-12 & LP-13 Housing Project.
- Support QC team For Fire Alarm System Equipment Inspection.
- Coordination with procurement team & Client's Engineering team.
- Assist in Fire Alarm System Testing & Commissioning.
- Support Tender Team for Bidding.

List of Project:

• SALAK BUILDING PROJECT HOUSING # 12 & 13

Client: Chevron Geothermal Salak

- SUMPAL 8 NEW WELL & SURFACE FACILITY PROJECT
- USM (ULTRASONIC METERING) GRISSIK PERTAGAS
- USM (ULTRASONIC METERING) GRISSIK DURI

Client: Conoco Phillips Indonesia

2. PT. GASTECH ENGINEERING

Instrument Engineer (August 2014 – July 2015)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Prepare and Review Instrument Datasheet.
- P&ID Design.
- Prepare and Review Instrument Cable schedule, Instrument Loop Diagram, Instrument Hook-Up Drawing, Instrument Location Plant.
- Prepare I/O List.
- Prepare and ReviewInstrument Design Basis.
- Review SCADA Design Basis.

List of Project:

• SUBAN 2 – FLOWLINE & FACILITIES PROJECT (ACCELERATION)

Client: PT. Shaftindo Energi (Conoco Phillips Contactor)

• Re-Engineering SUBAN 2 – FLOWLINE & FACILITIES PROJECT

Client: PT. Shaftindo Energi (Conoco Phillips Contactor)

• FEED FOR ADDITIONAL COMPRESSOR

Client: KSO Pertamina EP – Indospec Energy Limau

• PIPELINE SM-PTG CIKANDE

Client: PT. Banten Inti Gasindo

3. PT. RESINDO RESOURCES

Instrument Engineer (November 2013 – June 2014)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Prepare and Review Instrument Datasheet.
- P&ID Design.
- Prepare and Review Instrument Cable schedule, Instrument Loop Diagram, Instrument Hook-Up Drawing, Instrument Location Plant.
- Prepare I/O List.
- Contact Vendor.

- Review Instrument Design Basis.
- Review SCADA Design Basis.

List of Project:

• PAKISTAN DEEP WATER CONTAINER PORT-PHASE 1

Client: South Asia Pakistan Terminal (SAPT)

• SULPHURIC LONG CIRCULATION UPGRADE

Client: PT. VALE, Tbk

• HSFO MAIN TANK AUTOMATION

Client: PT. VALE, Tbk

4. PT. CINOVASI REKAPRIMA

Jr. Instrument Engineer

(March 2013 – July 2013)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Supervision of Variable Message Sign (VMS) installation progress in 14 location
- Attending weekly progress meeting and give written report to client (PT. Jasa Marga, Tbk).
- Prepare Bid Document and Design for Money and Train Magazine.
- Build a good relationship with the contractor.

List of Project:

• SURVEY TELEMETERING (Ramba and Bunyu Island)

Client: Pertamina EP

• JASA KONSULTANSI PENGAWASAN PEMASANGAN VMS TAHAP III.

Client: PT. Jasa Marga, Tbk

• JASA KONSULTANSI PERANCANGAN DAN LELANG MONEY AND MAGAZINE TRAIN OPERASIONAL

Client: PT. Jasa Marga, Tbk

5. PT. DAGO ENGINEERING (LAPI-ITB Project)

Jr. Instrument Engineer

(May 2012 – December 2012)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Prepare Instrument data sheet for control valve, flow instrument, Transmitter, etc.
- Prepare Specification Document for Instrument, I/O Point Calculation.
- Make coordination with any discipline such as: piping, Mechanical, Process.
- Review prepared drawing and document to comply with the code, standards and specifications for correctness and possibility to be fabricated.
- Control Valve Sizing.
- Prepare HAZOP Analysis.
- PAGA & CCTV Design.

List of Project:

• FEED TOTAL PROJECT KAMOJANG UNIT V

Client: Pertamina Geothermal

• JASA KONSULTANSI PERANCANGAN (FEED) DAN FEASIBILITY STUDY JALUR PIPA TRANSMISI GAS ARUN - BELAWAN

Client : Pertamina Gas

6. PT. ALKMAAR ASIA PACIFIC

Jr. Software Engineer

(November 2010 – November 2011)

Job Description & Responsibility:

- Design logic Equation for railway signalling.
- Do simulation appropriate with standard Operating Procedure that produced by main contractor.
- Coordination with hardware engineer.

List of Project:

• RET - Rotterdam

Client: GE - US

REFERENCES

Dwi Trisno Susanto

Honeywell

Project Manager

Mobile: +628128250198

Ramanda Achman

PT. Sarku Enjineering Utama

Engineering Manager

Mobile: +628128250198

Made Boyke Ismaya

PT. Alkmaar Asia Pacific

Senior Signalling Engineer

Mobile: +6285624804180

Devid

PT. Chevron Pacific Indonesia

Drilling & Completion Engineer

Mobile: +6281532783839

Akhmadi Pranoto

PT. Tegma Engineering

Instrument Engineer

Mobile: +6285720033269

Asep Sofyan

STC JO

I&C Comissioning Engineer

Mobile: +6281223736763

Arif Rizki Nugroho

WIKA Construction

Civil & Structure Engineer

Mobile: +6281297004309

Aji Rizki Febianto

JGC Indonesia

Civil & Structure Engineer

Mobile: +6285869999319